A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5298-aa
James Branch Cabell Collection 1919-1938
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5298-aa
27 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1993 July 7
Item Listing
- Letters
  - James Branch Cabell, Dumbarton Grange, Dumbarton, Virginia, to American author and journalist Benjamin DeCasseres, 1919 Nov 22; TLS, 1 p.
    acknowledging DeCasseres' praise of his work and returning praise, and hoping that he will read
    Jurgen
    "which attempts to carry out the theories of "Beyond Life"
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1919 Dec 6; TLS, 1 p.
    commenting that DeCasseres'
    The Shadow-Eater
    is one of his favorite books and that Jules de Gaultier is unknown to him
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1920 Jan 12; TLS, 1 p.
    hoping he can "eventually win through
    to the bitter end," praising DeCasseres' article on "The Immortality of the Soul," and encouraging "the debut of those ten or twelve unpublished books"
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1920 Apr 2; TLS, 1 p.
    expressing enjoyment of DeCasseres'
    Smart Set
    "Movies" and thanking him for a compliment
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1920 June 28; TLS, 1 p.
    commenting on his pleasure at reading his article in the "Literary Supplement" of The Evening Post, with AN at bottom
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1922 Aug 26; TLS, 1 p.
    expressing his pleasure upon receiving the inscribed copy of
    Chameleon
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1922 Dec 10; TLS, 1 p.
    declining an offer to do the introduction to
    because of trying to finish his new book [
    The High Place
    ] by the first of the year
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1922 Dec 17; TLS, 1 p.
    regretfully declining the offer to do the introduction while working on
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1924 Mar 5; TLS, 1 p.
    expressing his pleasure at having
    "in its handsome new dress," and planning to compare the two versions
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1925 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell, Richmond, Virginia, to Benjamin De Casseres, 1925 Oct 10; TLS, 1 p.
    expressing profound pleasure in reading
    Sex in Inhibitia
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1926 Dec 1; TLS, 1 p.
    thankful for receipt of
    Portraits on Galvanized Iron
    and
    The Boy of Bethlehem
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1928 Feb 16; TLS, 1 p.
    concerning the latter's proposed essay on Poictesmism
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1928 Aug 29; TLS, 1 p.
    thanking him for the interesting paper on Poictesmism, and expressing regret in its not being published
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1929 Nov 5; TLS, 1 p.
    thanking him for
    The Superman in America
    pamphlet
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1930 Apr 10; TLS, 1 p.
    referring to an essay sent by DeCasseres
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1930 Sep 16; TLS, 1 p.
    sending his thanks for the "June Thinker"
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1932 Jan 16; TLS. 1 p.
    saying he will send a copy of
    These Restless Heads
    as soon as he has it, and wishing the best for DeCasseres'
    The Elect and the Damned
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1932 Jan 19; TLS, 1 p.
    thanking him for "arranging the introduction" between Japan and himself
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1932 Apr 2; TLS, 1 p.
    concerning his name in a Japanese magazine, and mentioning
    The Restless Heads
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1932 Apr 8; TLS, 1 p.
    thanking him for the Japanese article, a criticism of his work
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1934 Feb 27; TLS, 1 p.
    forwarding a copy of
    Smirt
  - James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres, 1936 Apr 24; TLS, 1 p.
    expressing pleasure at receiving his book
    The Muse of Lies
    , and sending a belated copy of
    Preface to the Past
  - James Branch Cabell, Poynton Lodge, Ophelia, Virginia, to Benjamin De Casseres, 1936 Aug 28; TLS, 1 p.
    acknowledging receipt of the copy of
    , which he found on his way through Richmond
  - James Branch Cabell, Richmond, Virginia, to Benjamin De Casseres, 1938 Nov 4; TLS, 1 p.
    expressing gratitude for the heart-warming letter concerning a comment on Cabell's book
  - Christmas Cards from Priscilla Bradley Cabell and James Branch Cabell, Cards, 2 items